## **Tor Francis**

Philadelphia, PA | 678-790-2697 | torfrancis447@gmail.com linkedin.com/tor-francis | Portfolio | dev.to/torfrancis447

### **SUMMARY**

A highly motivated and natural people-person software developer with experience designing and developing full-stack and front-end applications in Ruby on Rails, PostgreSQL, and React. Proven ability to provide excellent end-users experience with years of experience in sales and team management.

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Ruby on Rails, PostgreSQL, Javascript, React, HTML, CSS, Material UI, Nextjs, Bootstrap, SQL, NextJs, AWS S3, Sqlite3, Git, Visual Studio Code, REST, APIs, Bcrypt, TailwindCSS, MongoDB, Node.js

### **TECHNICAL PROJECTS**

# Moodify - Github

An app for user's find music that matches their mood on Spotify

- Front-end-only project using HTML/CSS/vanilla JavaScript that accesses data from Spotify API to query playlists.
- Implemented toggleable CSS mode and In browser music player.

## Gamer's Paradise - Github | Demo

An app where users can keep track of games they would like to play

- Created a React app using Bootstrap for the CSS and React Router for client-side routing.
- Utilized a frontend API to fetch Video game data to be able to search for games currently on the market.

### Dev Hunt - Github

A job board app for candidates looking for developer jobs and companies looking to hire talent

- Implemented AWS S3 for document storage and Image storage.
- A full-stack application that follows RESTful API conventions including Authentication and Authorization.
- Used front-end API for email notifications.

## **EXPERIENCE**

# Ainley's Search Group

Philadelphia, PA

Recruiter

06/2022 - 09/2022

- Consulted with clients to obtain a precise understanding of the technical job description and requirements to fill
  positions with high-quality candidates in the manufacturing industry.
- Contributed to the acquisition of a major chemical Manufacturer.

### Frank's Recruitment Group

Philadelphia, PA

Recruitment consultant

01/2022 - 05/2022

- Participate in business development to identify top accounts, target skill sets, and assess clients' ServiceNow needs.
- Negotiating employment offers for candidates in the ServiceNow industry.
- Exceeded expectation of placing a candidate with a client within 3 months starting.

# **Extra Space Storage**

Philadelphia, PA

District Team Lead

05/2016 - 01/2022

- Managed 7 different properties with up to 800 concurrent customers
- Led a team of 20 individuals to drive revenue and key performance indicators for a Fortune 500 company
- Exceeded expectation of property occupancy 4 years in a row and maintained occupancy rate of over 90% for 1 year.

#### **EDUCATION**

# Flatiron School

Philadelphia, PA

Full Stack Web Development program

Rigorous coursework learning and applying the fundamentals of Javascript, React, SQL, and Ruby on Rails.

10/ 2022 - 03/2023

# **Penn State University**

Philadelphia, PA